<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Raúl Negrón&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://raulnegron.me/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Raúl Negrón&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://raulnegron.me/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Server-side JavaScript, available in 6 flavors</title>
      <link>https://raulnegron.me/2019/server-side-javascript-flavors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raulnegron.me/2019/server-side-javascript-flavors/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading up on JavaScript these past few months. I feel like there used to be a stigma against the language during my time at university, and maybe there still is. I dug up and read a book I once bought called JavaScript: The Good Parts by Douglas Crockford. It&amp;rsquo;s outdated now, but I used to joke that if &amp;ldquo;The Good Parts&amp;rdquo; could be described in 172 pages&amp;hellip; Well, suffice it to say, I was not very encouraged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full-Stack Project: vg-stack (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://raulnegron.me/2019/vgstack-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raulnegron.me/2019/vgstack-1/</guid>
      <description>Motivation In the web development space, tools and best-practices change quite frequently. At one point in the not-so-distant past, a LAMP stack was the go-to approach for launching a web application. These days, PHP is the #8 most popular programming language (according to a company with the name &amp;ldquo;The Importance Of Being Earnest&amp;rdquo;), while Python and JavaScript rank above it.
One of the reason for this change has to do with the growing trend towards microservice architectures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identity and Equality in Python</title>
      <link>https://raulnegron.me/2018/dev-python-strings-identity-vs-equality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raulnegron.me/2018/dev-python-strings-identity-vs-equality/</guid>
      <description>I would consider Python to be the programming language I&amp;rsquo;m most comfortable writing code in. There&amp;rsquo;s plenty to love, and one of its more recognizable features is its simple to read syntax. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard the phrase &amp;ldquo;executable pseudocode&amp;rdquo; thrown around before, and its easy to see where the comparisons come from.
A great side effect of sporting such a relatively simple to understand syntax is its mass appeal, with people jumping in with little programming knowledge and using Python to jump start their new coding adventures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Game Boy development on Mac</title>
      <link>https://raulnegron.me/2018/starting-gb-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raulnegron.me/2018/starting-gb-dev/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know what inspired it, but recently I got the idea that programming for an old game console would make for a fun project. Apart from giving me an excuse to write code in a language other than Python, it&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do ever since I learned that programming was at the heart of all the great games I&amp;rsquo;ve played throughout the years. So, I decided to find out how feasible it would be to program for one of these old school gaming systems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
